《越狱》第四季 第五集
Prison.Break.S04E05
《越狱》剧情回顾
Previously on Prison Break.
六位持卡人都参与了会议
It was a meeting between all six cardholders.
这下我们知道其他五个持卡人是谁了
Now we know who has the other five cards.
你的鼻子流血了
Your nose is bleeding.
-我是科尔・普发  -欢迎来到洛杉矶
-I'm Cole Pfeiffer. -Welcome to Los Ageles.
他叫蒂博格
He's name is Teodoro Bagwell
曾和我们一起在巴拿马
He was with us in Panama
现在他也来到了洛杉矶
and now he's here in Los Angeles.
他有一本书  本来属于惠斯勒
and he has a book that used to belong to Whistler
马宏认为这本书对我们打入内部有帮助
and Mahone thinks this book has a plan for the break-in.
科尔・普发没来参加我们的会议
Cole Pfeiffer do not arrive for our meeting.
你没拿到锡拉
You don't have Scylla?
似乎你的朋友惠斯勒不是唯一一个
It seems your friend Whistler wasn't the only one
-想找锡拉的人  你知道这事吗  -不知道
-looking into Scylla.You know anything about that? -No.
我在找杀我儿子的人
I'm looking for the man who killed my son.
他是一个职业杀手
This man is a professional assassin.
非裔美国人  六尺四寸
He's African American, six-foot, four,
大概220磅
about 220 pounds.
我们尽可能的优化了图像
We refined the image the best we could,
但是我们还是需要
but we're going to need
你的专家们把图像做的更清晰
one of your specialists to sharpen the video
这样我们才能辨认出其他人
so we can I.D. the rest of them.
好的  我会尽力的
All right, I'll see what I can do.
而且  我也见过那些技术人员能做什么
But I've seen what those tech guys are capable of.
有时候他们只能...
Sometimes, it's...
等一下  我认识这个人
Wait a sec, I know this guy.
这个人和我在一个大楼工作
This guy works in my building.
这是格里芬・奥林
That's Griffin Oren.
-你认识他  -还很了解他
-You know him? -I know of him.
他是财政部洛杉矶分部的头
He's the head of Treasury's L.A. bureau.
既然他和你在一栋大楼里  你就能接近他了
Well, if he's in your building you can get close to him.
-我需要一个理由  -那你就自己编一个吧
-I would need a reason. -Well, you make something up.
就说阿凯达组织偷了很多债券
Something about Al Qaeda using stolen bearer bonds
来资助地下活动  随便你
to finance shady operations, whatever.
不是吧  编造虚假言论
Come on, making false claims
损害政府威信
in matters affecting government?
那可是要判五年刑的
That's up to five years in prison.
欢迎成为我们的一员  赛尔夫探员
Welcome to the club, Agent Self.
感谢你来见我
Thanks for meeting me.
我一直想出来见你
I would have come out to see you,
但是我不能走太远
but I can't travel that far...
不好意思
I'm sorry...
你说你有些照片要给我看
but you said that you had some pictures to show me.
就是他
That's him.
我会尽快和你联系
I'll get in touch with you
一旦我...
as soon as...
一旦我查出是谁干的
as soon as... I find out.
不是你的错
You didn't do this.
你其实一直是个好人
In your heart, you are a really good man.
因此我嫁给你
That's why I married you.
因此我和你成家
That's why I started a family with you.
还记得你经常带着文件回家
Remember when you used to bring your files home
我总是求你把那些东西留在办公室
and I would beg you to leave that stuff at work?
但是当你看到了坏人
But when you have a monster in your sights...
只有抓到他
you can't focus
你才能在意你身边的人
until you get him.
我以前很恨你那样
I used to hate that about you.
现在只有一件事能安慰我自己
Right now it's the only thing that lets me sleep,
那就是我相信
because I know...
你会抓到凶手
you're going to get him.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你好啊 布伦尼
Hey there, Blauney.
只是
Just, uh...
做一些调查
doing a little research.
关于伽特公司的
Gate-related?
这样才更能让我发挥实力
I'm adding a little flourish to my pitch.
我不能像笼中之鸟一样
"Like the caged macaw
无法展翅翱翔
who cannot spread her wings."
其实  科尔
You know, Cole...
我一直在想你应该少花点时间空想
I was thinking maybe you should spend a little less time
多花一点时间做点实事
practicing and a little more time actually pitching.
我的意思是  世界第一的销售员
I mean, number one salesman in the world?
我们一直盼望着
We're all just waiting with bated breath
你能做点什么
to see what you can do around here.
唉
Ouch.
我知道
I know.
我们看见了他在那里
We saw him right here.
嘿
Hey.
你见过莎拉吗
You haven't seen Sara, have you?
没有
No.
你想回福克斯河
You want to end up back in Fox River,
就回去吧
you just go right ahead.
嘿  怎么了
Hey, what's going on?
-他想去找T-bag  -算你说对了
0He wants to look for T-Bag. -You're damn right.
我就是要找他  我们知道他有那本书
I want to look for him.We know he's got the bird book.
也知道那本书里写着打入内部的计划
We know the bird book's got the plan for the break-in.
而且我们今天在这儿看见那个混蛋了
And we saw that snake right here today.
我的意思是  我们是逃犯
All I'm saying is, it ain't safe
所以  我们来找另外一个逃犯
for a member of the Fox River Eight to be out there looking
-是非常不安全的  -没错  但是
-for another member of the Fox River Eight. -Yes, but...
贝里克  你和苏克雷一起去
Bellick, I want you to go with Sucre,
仔细查查这个地区  看看你能不能找到他的线索
canvass the area, see if you can get a lead on him.
那里有六栋大楼
There are like six big buildings over there.
他可能在任何一个里面
He could be in any one of them.
所以我说仔细查查
That's why it's called canvassing.
你知道吧  这可是在财政部里行动啊
You do realize this is the Treasury Department, right?
你让赛尔夫下几层楼
You tell Self to go down a few floors,
只要能看到那几台重要电脑
walk past the right computers
我们就会变成大富翁了
and we are billionaires.
拜托  我只要那张卡
Just the card, please.
当・赛尔夫  国土安全局
Don Self, Homeland Security.
-我需要马上与奥林先生会面  -他现在不在
-I need to see Mr. Oren right away. -He's not available.
我需要马上见他
Ma'am, I need to see him
否则的话  成千上万美国人
right away, otherwise hundreds of American lives
的生命将会受到威胁
will be in jeopardy.
当・赛尔夫  国土安全局
Don Self, Homeland Security.
去和大厅里的安吉拉说
Talk to Angela down the hall.
长官  对不起我闯了进来
Sir, I'm sorry to barge in here,
但是这事很紧急
but this is urgent.
我知道
I'm sure it is.
去和大厅里的安吉拉说
Talk to Angela down the hall.
长官  我们听说有一些债券被偷了
Sir,we are hearing chatter about some stolen bearer bonds,
而且我们也相信这个事情和阿凯达组织有关
and we have reason to believe that Al Qaeda operatives...
你有债券的号码吗
You have serial numbers?
我没有
No, I do not.
介意转过去吗
Mind turning around?
不介意
Not at all.
六小时后  我要去亚洲
I leave for Asia in six hours.
他找到了
He's got it.
在那之前
Until then...
我要和几个部门主管开会
I've got meetings with the bureau chiefs
包括联邦调查局  中情局  国土安全局
of the FBI, the CIA and Homeland Security.
信号没了
It's gone.
如果你现在告诉我的事情真的重要
If what you tell me is actually important,
我会从你的上司那里知道
I'll hear about it from your boss.
除非那样
Until then...
否则一切事情去和大厅里的安吉拉说
talk to Angela down the hall.
而且  你如果在没有我的允许下
And if you set foot
再进入我的办公室
in my office again without my prior consent,
我会让你在阿拉斯加
I will see to it that you spend the rest
边防站呆到退休
of our career running border security in Alaska.
拿到了吗
Did we get it?
怎么了
What happened?
什么怎么了
What do you mean what happened?
只有几秒钟信号  然后就没了
We had it for two seconds and then it disappeared.
一定是在保险箱里
It's in the safe.
他办公室里有个超安全的保险箱
He has this crazy safe in his office.
信号肯定是被保险箱屏蔽了
That must have been blocking the transmission.
我确定卡就在那里放着
I'll bet you that's where he keeps the card.
那我们就要想办法打开保险箱
So we need to get into that safe.
相信我  绝对没办法打开的
Trust me, there's no way to crack that thing.
过几个小时  我就会有其他持卡人
Look,I'll have the enhanced images of the other
清晰的照片了  我们再从那里入手
cardholders in a couple of hours,we'll go from there.
你能找到大楼的图纸  对吧
You can access the building's blueprints, right?
我不能再回去了
I can't go back up there.
没让你回去  我们来处理这个问题
No one's asking you. We'll take care of that.
算了吧  你们连正门都进不去
Come on, you'll never get past the front door, okay?
就算他们不认识你们
Even if they don't recognize you,
你还要有出入的通行证  上面有...
you need a security card that matches...
找到图纸  然后来找我  好吗
Get the blueprints and get back here, all right?
好吧
Yeah...
莎拉  出什么事了
Sara, what happened?
我很好  但是有人跟踪我
I'm fine, but someone was following me.
我在离这一英里左右的地方甩甩掉了他
I lost him about a mile back.
我觉得他不可能跟着我到这里了
I don't think there's any way he could have
-我很确定  -他长什么样子
-followed me here.I made sure of that. -What'd he look like?
很高  黑人  还有胡子
Uh, tall, black. He had a beard.
是这个人吗
Is this the guy?
是的
Yeah.
这是谁
Who's that?
是他杀了我儿子
That's the man who killed my son.
现在冲着我们来了
Now he's coming to kill us.
你第一次是在哪里看见的他
Where were you the first time that you saw him?
第一次
The very first time?
回家的时候
Walking home.
他有没有在街上和你打招呼
He didn't just run into you on the street?
那你之前在哪里
Where were you before that?
提朗格
The Towne Lounge.
是不是酒吧
Is that a bar?
有什么问题吗
Do you have a problem with that?
不是  我只是想知道你在那里待了多长时间
No, I just want to know how long you were there.
莎拉
Sara,
我要找到这个人  而且我需要你的帮助
I need to find this guy and I can't do it without your help.
我不管你为什么要去那个酒吧  或者你干了什么
I don't care why or what you were doing in the bar.
我就是想知道你在那里待了多长时间
I just really want to know how long you were there.
好吧  几个小时
Okay. A couple hours.
谢谢你  他肯定留下了什么蛛丝马迹
Thank you. So something must have tipped him off.
你付的是现金  对吗
You paid cash, right?
当然了
Of course.
但是布鲁斯给我的信用卡没了
But the credit card that Bruce gave me is gone.
什么信用卡
What credit card?
这些是安全检查点
These are the security checkpoints.
如果你没有这个  你一处也过不去
You can't get past one of those unless you have one of these.
我们能不能伪造几个
Any way we can forge it?
当然了  如果你有两个星期
Sure, if you have two weeks and access
并且能进入大楼的主机
to the building's mainframe maybe.
好像十楼没有
Well, doesn't look like there are any security checkpoints
-安全检查点  -是的
-on the tenth floor. -No, just that
只有能到十楼的几个地方有
all the access points to the tenth floor.
但是  如果你能神奇的
But if you could somehow magically appear
出现在大厅的中间  你就安全了
and wind up in the middle of the hallway, you'd be fine,
不过那里到处都是政府官员
except for all the government officials who'd be swarming
他们一眨眼就能把你抓住
around and who would arrest you in a heartbeat.
如果你把我们带到停车场
And if you can get us into the parking structure,
保安会查我们的车吗
will security check our van?
当然了  车里可以藏罪犯  为什么不查
Sure. Transporting known felons, why not?
那么  停车场
So, the parking garage.
就是我们进去的地方
This is our point of entry.
我们需要关于保险箱的细节
We need the details to the safe.
有一个徽章在保险箱上面
Okay, the, um, the safe has an insignia on it.
看起来和这个很像
It looks something like this.
你要用点这个
You're gonna need some of this.
我在洛杉矶找到了莎拉・唐克雷蒂
I got a positive ID of Sara Tancredi in Los Angeles.
这意味着迈克尔・斯科菲尔德也在
That means Michael Scofield was here.
还有林肯・布鲁斯  为什么
That means Lincoln Burrows is here. Why?
莎拉  是吧
Sara, huh?
她就是一个狡猾的小贱人
She's a slippery little bitch, isn't she?
你没什么时间耍滑头了  格雷琴
Time is not on your side, Gretchen.
可能你一直没注意
Maybe you hadn't noticed,
既然你可以一直
but since you seem to be somewhat immune
抵抗对你身体的折磨
to physical coercion,
我们决定换个方式
we've decided to move on.
鼻子是一个进化的奇迹
The nose is an evolutionary marvel.
我们的大脑会告诉我们
Our brain has been constructed so that certain aromas...
咖啡豆  蓝莓的气味对我们的身体是有益的
...coffee beans, blueberries that are helpful to our body,
我们可以感觉到这些东西是令人舒适的
we perceive as pleasant.
相反的  有一些气味以为着死亡
Whereas other smells that signify death,
疾病
disease.
开始的症状有恶心  头晕
Initial symptoms include nausea, dizziness,
红眼  所有你现在所感受到的
burning eyes, all of which you are experiencing right now.
如果长时间接近会造成眩晕
Prolonged exposure will lead to faintness,
快速的失去意识
rapid degradation of your mental faculties.
告诉我
Tell me.
我什么都不知道
I don't know anything.
再给你一天时间
You've got one more day.
上等货色
Top of the line.
根据生理特征设计
It's a biometric design,
而且只有奥林的指纹可以打开
and only Oren's fingerprint will open it.
那我们就从他碰过的东西上取下他的指纹
So we lift his prints off something he touched.
触摸器知道皮肤触摸的感觉
The pad knows what human skin feels like.
如果我们骗它  它就会拉响警报
If we try to trick it, we'll set off the alarm.
而且还有12位的密码设计
And then there's the 12-digit key code.
那铰链呢
What about the hinges?
链接着警报
Wired to the alarm.
那我们就钻吧
We drill it.
可能可以从金属的外层钻
Through the outer layer of steel maybe,
但是这个东西是由7.5英寸厚
but the bones of this thing are three-quarters inch
钴合金做成的
of cobalt alloy hard plate.
我们没时间用钻的方法
Drilling's not gonna work, not in our timeframe.
简单来说  我们有办法进入停车场
All right, so basically, we have a way to get you
但是你们别忘了
into the garage, which, in case you guys forgot,
这样的话会给我多加四项罪名
that puts me on the hook for another four charges.
而且你们还没有办法到十楼
But no way to get you up to the tenth floor.
就算你们到十楼了
But let's say you do get up to the tenth floor.
你们还要在光天化日之下  在奥林的办公室里
Then we need to get you into Oren's office for an hour
待一个小时
during the middle of the day.
接着我们就要期盼
Then, we need to hope
奥林的同事不会听到
that not one of Oren's co-workers is gonna hear
因为要打开保险箱使用的
the extremely loud drill that you're gonna be using
巨大的钻机的声音
to break into a safe that I'm telling you
而且这个保险箱我们是不可能打开的
cannot be broken into.
你知不知道  还有
Do you understand there are Homeland agents
由安全局的探员设计的保安措施
whose sole job is to design safety measures
以确保这个地方是坚不可摧的
to make this structure impregnable.
以前在福克斯河也是这样
Yeah. They had those guys Fox River, too.
这个办公室是谁的
Whose office is this?
山姆・米尔顿  司法部的
Sam Middleton, Department of Justice.
这面墙正好在米尔顿和沃勒的中间
This wall separates Middleton from Warren.
我需要一些工具
I'm gonna need some supplies.
信用卡在10点32分的时候在酒吧用过
The credit card was used at the bar at 10:32.
你什么时候看到他的
What time did you see him?
大概11点的时候
About 11:00.
你当时走了多长时间了
And how long were you walking at that time?
10 15分钟
Ten, 15 minutes.
我们假设他在家接到了电话
Let's assume that he was at his place when we received the call.
开车18分钟
That's an 18-minute drive
才能到圣佩德罗的提朗格酒吧
from the Towne Lounge Bar in San Pedro.
如果按平均30英里每小时计算
Averaging 30 miles an hour the whole way,
大概就是9英里的范围
that's a, that's a nine-mile radius.
那他就是在这个圈里
So he's gonna be somewhere around the perimeter of that circle.
他肯定是在高速公路附近
He's got to be mobile
半英里以内的地方
within a half mile of a major freeway.
10号  110号  405号
The 10, the 110, the 405.
没有固定住址  那我们就找旅店  对吗
No permanent address, so we're looking for hotels, right?
对  不要找帮客人停车的旅店
Yeah, but nowhere where you need to valet your car.
因为他要随时使用汽车
It's got to be readily accessible at all times.
而且  不要找
And somewhere you don't need
用信用卡付钱的地方  明白吗
to put a credit card down for incidentals. You got that?
我看看我能不能找到
I'll see what I can do.
快点
Hurry.
崔什娜  我要一杯柠檬茶
Trishanne, I'm gonna need a mug of tea with lemon.
抱歉  科尔  我现在走不开
I'm sorry, Cole. I can't leave the desk right now.
好帮手还真难找
Good help is so hard to find.
有什么可以效劳的吗
May I help you?
我们是高谷保险的人
We're with Upper Valley Insurance.
这人继承了一份10万美金的遗产
And this man just came into a $100,000 inheritance.
我们找不到他  所以现在提供
We can't track him down, so we're offering
百分之十的费用
a ten percent finder's fee
给提供线索的人
to anyone who can point us in his direction.
天啊  什么  1万美金
Oh, my gosh. What, $10,000?
对
Yeah.
抱歉  我不认识他
I'm sorry. I don't recognize him.
好的  如果你见到他  麻烦打电话给我们
Okay,so if you do see him,would you please give us a call?
谢谢
Thank you.
伽特
"GATE"?
成功通向卓越
"Greatness Achieved Through Excellence."
做玩具吗
A toy?
你能解释下吗
You want to try to explain this?
铝粉和氧化铁的混合物
Mix aluminum powder with iron oxide.
加热
Add a little heat.
喂  谢谢你回电话  山姆
Hey. Yeah, well, thanks for calling me back, Sam.
不  我知道你安排了庭审
Yeah. No,I just,I know you have these trial dates coming up
我们只是想确认你们有确凿的证据
and we just want to make sure you have everything
给这帮混蛋定罪
you need to convict these bastards.
太好了
Okay, that's terrific.
好的  待会见
All right, I'll see you then.
好的
All right,
我们约好吃午餐
we're gonna have lunch.
我会尽量拖延他
I'll keep him out of his office for as long as I can.
祝你好运
Good luck.
好的
All right.
-喂  -有他的消息吗
-Hello. -Hey, any sign of him?
没有  我们查了10栋楼了
No, we checked about ten buildings,
但没发现什么
but nothing so far.
算了吧  我们要找下一张卡
Well, scrap it; we're going after the next card.
在圣摩尼卡和西世纪街角等我
Meet me on the corner of Santa Monica and Century West.
你好  查理
Hey, Charlie.
美国队昨晚又输了
Yankees lost again last night.
对  至少粉丝们在
Yeah, well, at least our fans show up
第5局前到了  对不对
before the fifth inning, right?
祝你愉快  查理
Have a good day, all right, Charlie?
你也是  赛尔夫先生
You, too, Mr. Self.
我跟你们说清楚
I'm letting you guys know right now.
你们要是被抓了  别提我的名字
If you get buzzy,don't mention my name.
准备好了
We're ready.
开始
Now.
1  2  3
One, two, three.
嗨
So...
两个邋遢鬼来过
a couple of scruffy guys walk in,
说他们是保险公司的
tell me they're from the insurance company
如果我说出你的下落  他们就给我1万美金
and they offer me $10,000 if I know where you are.
直觉告诉我
Something tells me
这里有更高的报酬
there's a better offer on the table.
当然  崔什娜
Well, I'll be, Trishanne.
你刚刚抓了个小精灵
You just caught yourself a leprechaun.
就像传说那样
And as the legend goes,
你能实现一个愿望  任何愿望
you got yourself one wish, anything in the world.
是吗
Oh, really?
我会帮你实现
And I am bound to grant it.
-是吗  -恩
-Yeah? -Mm-hmm.
你的分红支票还在我台面
Well, your commencement check's sitting on my desk
等你签收
waiting to be signed.
这倒是个不错的报酬
That's a pretty nice pot of gold.
在你开口前...
Before you say another word...
告诉你
Now, it's true
精灵不会拒绝捕获者的要求
leprechauns cannot refuse their captor's demands,
但一旦他们认为
but if they deem her
她是个贪婪之徒
to be greedy or covetous,
不管她要求什么  都会伴随着
whatever she desires will certainly be accompanied
可怕的诅咒
with disastrous tidings.
这也是传说
Or so the legend goes.
只要分红的百分之三
Three percent of your commission
然后一笔勾销
from here on out.
成交
Done.
当・赛尔夫来找你
Don Self to see you.
你可以进去了
You can go right on in.
-谢谢  祝您愉快  -你也是
-Thank you. Have a great day. -You too.
嘿  山姆
Hey, Sam.
很高兴见到你
Great to meet you.
我也是
Same here.
谢谢你能临时
Oh, thanks again for squeezing me in
挤出时间给我
on such short notice.
我想我们倒是
I figure we had so much
还有很多时间  这是最好的办法
to get through, this'd be the best way.
我以为我们出去吃
I-I thought we were going out for lunch.
有问题吗
Is there a problem?
实际上...
actually, um...
我是吃素的
I'm a vegetarian.
新的减肥食谱  不过楼下
It's a new diet, b-b-but there's
倒是有个不错的地方
a great place down the street,
我请客
and it'll be my treat.
伊利斯
Elise.
是  先生
Yes, sir?
我出去吃饭
I'm heading out for lunch.
抓好
Hold it there.
不好意思  我想取些
Sorry, I was just coming in to...
女洗手间没有手纸了
There's no more TP in the ladies room.
我们一会就送去
We'll get right on that.
能不能现在就要
How about you get it right now?
这是这里最好的了
Best we got in here.
你们干活应该有点条理
You guys need to get better organized.
搜索到了53家旅馆
53 hotels match the search criteria.
你知道我刚才
You know I read, I read this article
看了一篇文章
a little while ago, right?
讲的是先天所有和后天培养的关系
About the whole, uh, nature versus nurture thing,
每个人之所以生得不同
and it turns out, it's all kind of a mishmash
是因为DNA早就决定了一切
because DNA trumps everything.
我很信这个
And I believe it, because
因为我和我哥我姐生在同样的家庭
I mean, I grew up in the same house,
我和我哥上同样的学校
uh, went to the same school as my brother,
他现在是数学系教授
who's a math professor,
我姐也是个儿科医生
My sister's a pediatrician.
我却是个贼
And I'm a thief who blows his money
把钱都花在妓女身上了
on hookers and coke.
同样  斯科菲尔德是天才
So, like the same way Scofield's hardwired to be a genius,
你生来就是执法的
and you are always gonna be a lawman, right?
我想说的是  无论是谁
I mean, whoever this guy is,
都不想变成杀人犯吧
you think he wanted to grow up to be a murderer?
不会吧
Probably not.
说话小心点
Be very careful choosing the next words
别张嘴就来
that come out of your mouth.
我只是想说
I... I'm just saying.
我们就是我们自己
We are who we are.
杰克  现在到1018办公室来
Jake. I'm gonna need you in front of room 1018. Now.
-怎么了  -抱歉  女士
-What's going on?  -I apologize, ma'am,
我们要妨碍到你了
but we're gonna be in your way
大概得弄一个半小时
for the next 90 minutes or so.
-布莱克  -来了
-Black? -Yeah.
不好意思  女士
Excuse me, ma'am,
有没有插座
but where can I plug in?
你现在可以用办公室里的
For now, you can go in there,
但我老板吃完午饭回来后
but when my boss gets back from lunch,
你就...
you're gonna...
保险箱应该在这面墙后面
The safe should be somewhere behind this wall.
你钻穿保险箱之后
As soon as you're through the steel,
我的铝热剂也准备好了
I'll have the thermite ready.
怎么了
What is it?
你这样多久了
How long has it been happening?
小事一桩
It's not a big deal.
你13岁的时候这可不是什么小事
It was a big deal when you were 13.
跟我保证不要告诉莎拉
Just promise me you won't tell Sara.
莎拉是医生  她能帮你的
Sara's a doctor. She can help.
我只是不适应这边燥热的天气  行么?
Look, I acclimating to the warmer climate, all right?
拜托  我们还有活干呢
Come on. We've got work to do.
开始吧
Let's go.
我不知道这个公司是干什么的
I don't know what this company is up to, but it sure
但看上去涉及一大笔钱
sounds like there's a whole lot of money involved.
不清楚
I don't know.
丽莎・特巴克刚刚飞到老挝对吧?
Lisa Tabak just hopped a flight to Laos, didn't she?
好像是
Yeah, I guess.
而且格里芬・奥林刚说过
And now Griffin Oren just said
他要去亚洲
he was going somewhere in Asia.
打到里层了
Down to the cobalt.
好的
Right.
想喝点什么
What can I get you?
耽误你一点时间
Just a moment of your time.
我是私人侦探
I'm a private investigator,
我为一个叫做
and I'm working with a woman
莎拉・唐克雷蒂的女人工作
named Sara Tancredi,
她之前来过你这
and she was recently a patron of yours.
我不想被扯进来
I don't want to get involved.
她为了躲这个人
She moved all the way across the country
从东部躲到西部来
to get away from this guy.
帮我  不要让这个人找到她
Help me find him before he finds her.
莎拉和你聊过很多吧
Last time, Sara had a broken jaw.
他走的时候我在前门
I was standing by the front door when he left.
之后看到他经过
A second later I saw him come past,
从他的车里拿了些东西出来
take something out of his car.
你记得不记得是什么样的车
Do you remember what the car looked like?
灰色轿车  很像租车公司的车
Gray. A sedan,sort of like one of those rental cars,you know?
有什么事么
You need something?
想请你
Just a small...
帮个忙
kindness.
赚这300美元再容易不过了
That's the easiest $300 you'll ever make.
我们正忙着呢
We're working here.
我也是啊
So am I.
这有一堆信
There's a stack of letters
等着寄出去
that I need to put in the mail.
这种清洁剂会和皮革反应的
The chemicals, they don't react so good with leather.
你用的是什么  强碱吗
What are you using, lye?
等等
Wait, wait, wait.
听我说
Listen, we...
我们知道这很烦人
we know this is a hassle.
我们知道打扰到你工作了
We know we're disrupting your work
让你头疼了
and giving you a headache.
我们的工作每天都不得不打扰别人
We annoy a different person every day,
如果湿的地毯给弄脏了
but if this gets dirty while it's still wet,
就会留下脏印
it's gonna leave a stain,
我们就会被...
and... and, uh, and then we'll be
又回到这里了
back here all over again.
你为何不直接告诉我他们在哪里
Why don't you just tell me where they are
我把他们给抓来就是了
and I'll get them for you?
在他办公桌边上的电脑旁边
On the corner of his desk near his computer.
还要多久
How much longer?
还要几分钟  我们准备复制了
Another couple of minutes, and we'll be ready to copy.
格里芬在吗
Is Griffin in?
他现在在开会
He's in a meeting right now,
但你想的话我可以叫他出来
but I can pull him out if you'd like.
拜托了
If you could.
稍坐一会儿
Just have a seat in his office.
他马上就过来
He'll be right with you.
我们需要的
All we need is one more.
有人在里面
Some one's in there.
如果我听到他坐下的声音的话
If I could hear him sitting down, there's no way
他不可能听不到钻的噪音
he's not gonna hear the drill.
你可以手工做啊
You can do it manually.
能生成足够热量来激活铝热剂吗
Generate enough heat to activate the thermite?
拜托  我们离这个大概就16英尺了
Come on, man, we're like a 16th of an inch away from this.
能为你效劳吗?
Can I help you?
我打过电话来找你们的一个客人
I phoned earlier about one of your guests.
是开灰色轿车的吧
Gray sedan, right?
是的
Yeah, right.
是这个人吗
Is that the guy?
对  就是他
Yeah, that's him.
哪个房间
What room?
他住130房
He was in 130.
已经退房了
He checked out.
他...
Did, um...
他有没有提到他去哪儿
did he leave any clue as to where he was going?
我能看下房间吗
Do you mind if I look at the room?
19块一小时  59一晚
$19 an hour, $59 for the night.
行了  把钥匙给我吧
Fine, whatever, give me a key.
好的
Yes.
你想知道谁来找过你吗
You wanted to know if anyone came looking for you.
他们来过吗
Did they?
没有  我正想打电话给你说
No. I was just calling to let you know
我的任务已经完了
my shift was ending
但没人出现  好的
and nobody showed up. All right.
谢谢
Thank you.
把你手上那张纸
What do you say you give me
给我你觉得如何
that little piece of paper in your hand?
觉得怎么样
How's that sound, huh?
很抱歉让你等了
Sorry for keeping you.
做好离开的准备就是了
Just making sure you're ready for your trip.
我会的  我五分钟后出发
Well, I better be. I'm leaving in five minutes.
好的  如果我们
All right, and if we dial it down
-是吗  -我们别无选择
Sure? We don't have a choice.
开始了我会告诉你
I'll tell you when.
财政部长正焦急的等待你的到来
The finance minister's anxiously awaiting your arrival.
如果你还记得的话  我曾成功的
Well, if you recall, I successfully negotiated
和IMF及世界银行协商金融政策
financial policies with the IMF and World Bank.
处理老挝那边还不是小菜一碟
Pretty sure I can handle Laos.
现在
Now.
格里芬  现在我很清楚你的履历了
I'm well aware of your resume, Griffin.
搞定
Got it.
我们搞定了
We're in.
-明白  -老挝的恶性通货膨胀已被
-Got it. -The runaway inflation in Laos
粮食危机所取代
has given way to food riots
在越南首都
in the capital city of Vientiane,
死亡人数已超过200
where the death toll has risen over 200.
金融政策已走向死胡同
The monetary policy is a means to an end.
将军  我很清楚我们的终极目标
I'm aware of our final objective, General.
今天对我们来说很重要
This is an important day for us.
每个人都要清楚自己的角色
I need to make sure that everyone knows his role.
你完全可以在电话里面说清楚啊
You could've told me all of this on the telephone.
为什么非选今天过来
Why did you take today of all days to come down here
跑监狱里来骂我
and berate me in person?
过去几天发生的事情
Things have happened in the past few days
让我有点不安
that have made me somewhat uneasy.
今天我们得到确切消息说
Today we got confirmation
我们的目标之一在洛杉矶
that one of our targets is in Los Angeles.
实际上
That on top of the fact,
丽莎的保镖之一被杀
that one of Lisa's bodyguards was killed.
我觉得是因为她和那个土耳其人结婚的原因
I thought that was because she was married to that Turk.
那是官方的说法
That's the official story.
那是怎么回事
What is it then?
快点  快点
Come on, come on.
格里芬  你带卡了吗
Do you have your card on you, Griffin?
当然
Of course.
给我看下
I'd like to see it.
进行的如何
Where are we?
罗兰  说话
Talk to me Roland.
72%
72%.
我想看看
I'd like to see it.
一起工作过15年  你应该相信我
15 years working together, you think you'd trust me.
别演戏了
Don't turn this into an opera.
把卡给我
Just hand me the card.
开心吗
Happy?
从现在起  我要求
From now on, I'm asking that everyone
每个人都要随身带卡
keep their card on them at all times.
谁动的
Anyone makes a move,
有什么丢失了  打电话给我
anything goes missing, you call me.
到手了没
Did we get it?
-完了  -是的
-100. -Yeah.
我不清楚你如何吃下那只螃蟹的  当
I don't know how you eat that crap, Don.
-那个叫什么来着  豆豉吗  -是啊
-What was that called? Tempeh? -Yeah.
我看你很勉强才把他吞下去的
It looked like you could barely choke it down.
这个需要三思而后行
Yeah, well, it's an acquired taste.
打扰一下
Excuse us.
好的
All right, well,
我该回去工作了
it looks like I should be getting back to work.
很高兴和你一起
Oh. This was a pleasure.
很显然  有数以万计的假钞在市场中泛滥
Apparently, billions in counterfeit currency flooded the economy,
是什么引起这些问题呢
which is what caused it all.
我所不明白的是为什么
What I don't understand is why?
那些持卡人
I mean, so far all the cardholders
都是他们所在领域的专家
have been experts in their fields, right?
无论是在能源方面  物流方面
In-in energy, and logistics,
还是金融方面
and finance.
我是说  他们看起来
I mean, it looks like
想要摧毁这个国家
they're trying to tear the country down.
然后通过重建来获取利益
And then they profit by rebuilding it.
所以问题是  接下里会是什么
So the question is: what's next?
几天前我在一个酒吧里
I was at a bar earlier.
我没有喝酒  也没有发生任何的事情
And nothing happened, and I didn't drink.
听着  如果这让你很难受
But... Look, if-if this is too much for you...
不  不
No. No.
那么我们忘了它好了
Because, say the word, and we'll scrap the whole thing.
我答应你  以后不会再发生了
That's a promise. It's not going to happen again.
如果我不和你说的话  那么这就是一个谎言了
But it would be a lie not to tell you, and I...
我想你知道  我永远也不会欺骗你
want you to know that I'll never lie to you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
有人找你
Somebody's here for you.
找我
For me?
科尔・普发
Cole Pfeiffer.
你是星
Is your name Xing?
星先生还呆在纽约
Mr. Xing stayed behind in New York.
那么请坐吧
Well, have a seat then, uh--
有什么可以为您效劳的
What can I help you with?
你本该在两天之前交货的
You were supposed to deliver the item two days ago.
东西在哪里
Where is it?
什么在哪里啊
Where's what?
我赶很远的路过来的  普发先生
I've traveled a long way, Mr. Pfeiffer.
我的忍耐是有限度的
My patience is wearing thin.
耍小把戏对我们都没有好处
Playing games is not going to be good for either of us.
锡拉在哪里
Scylla. Where is it?
普发先生  我现在在工作
Mr. Pfeiffer? I'm at work.
我没有多余的时间和你交谈
It's not exactly like I can talk freely, you know.
我直接进入主题吧
Just-just tell me the latest.
主题 对吗
The latest?
如果你在截止日期之前
If you deliver it
把东西交给我
to me by the end of the day,
我会按我们约好的金额付款给你
I will pay you the sum that we agreed upon.
我想告诉你这有可能
As much as I'd like to tell you that were possible...
如果你明天给我
Get it to me by tomorrow
你将得到金额的50%
and you will receive 50% of your fee.
后天  25%
Two days, 25%.
大后天
Three days,
那么我就打爆你的头
I shoot you through the brain.
这就是主题
That is the latest.
没问题
No problem.
看起来这些尿不新鲜了
I thought that urine might be getting a little stale.
所以我给你带了一些新的来
So I brought you some more.
增强了影像的视频恢复了
Hey, the image enhancement for the video came back.
我发给你的收到了没
Did you get what I sent over?
三位持卡人吗
All three cardholders?
是的  前面两位持卡人
Yeah, well, for the first two,
我们可以获得一切我们想要的资料
we have names, addresses--
例如  名字  地址等等
everything we need to grab them.
莎拉
Sara.
但我们得不到任何有关将军的资料
But for the General... we got nothing.
这个家伙像石头里蹦出来的一样
This guy's a ghost.
你还好吧
You all right?
在巴拿马发生的大部分事情  我都不太清楚
Look,most of what happened to me in Panama is a total blank.
但
But, um,
当我被挟持的时候
when I was being held, I could hear
我隐约听到格雷琴在隔壁讲电话
Gretchen talking on the phone, in the next room.
她在接受
And she was taking orders
老大的指令
from the guy in charge.
她称他为将军
And she called him the General.
任务的指挥者吗
In charge of the mission?
不  我认为是公司的大老板
No, I think in charge of the Company.
我早告诉过你
I told you...
有机会时我们就应该杀了格雷琴
we should have killed Gretchen when we had the chance.
她会回来的
She'll come home.
她一直如此
She always has.
希望你是对的
You better be sure about that.
打扰一下
Excuse me, sir?
怎么了
What?
今天  有人在国家安全局
Someone at Homeland Security
通过增强影像搜索了你
did an enhanced image search on you today.
然而我们不知道原始图片...
We couldn't tell where the original picture...
谁
Who?
搜索人的名字
The guy who ordered it...
叫做当・赛尔夫
his name is Don Self.